{
    "id": "b4402410da434dc59df7ec5fa2eaecc7",
    "title": "Also, As Well, Either, Neither",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "0205ae0b56914958a390ab6cefbad2a8",
            "title": "Also, Either, Neither, Nor",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "‘I can’t swim.’ ‘………………….. can I.’",
                    "description": "After a negative idea, we can add another negative idea with neither.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Either",
                        "Neither",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Ruth didn’t turn up. Margaret didn’t ……………………………",
                    "description": "After mentioning a negative idea, we can add another negative idea by using ‘not…either’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "either",
                        "neither",
                        "also"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "James didn’t pass the test. ………………………… did Samuel.",
                    "description": "We can use neither / nor to mean ‘not … either’ after a negative idea.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Or",
                        "Nor",
                        "Either"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘I don’t like opera.’ ‘…………………………..’",
                    "description": "‘Neither do I’ means the same as ‘I don’t either.’",
                    "answers": [
                        "I don't either",
                        "Neither do I",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Our main need is not food, ………………………. jobs. It is education.",
                    "description": "Nor can follow not. It is more emphatic than or. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "or",
                        "nor",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "James was not at home, and ………………………… was Alice.",
                    "description": "Neither or nor can be used here",
                    "answers": [
                        "either",
                        "neither",
                        "also"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He neither smiled ………………………… looked at me.",
                    "description": "Neither…nor is used to join two negative ideas.",
                    "answers": [
                        "or",
                        "nor"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She not only sings she ………………………… dances.",
                    "description": "Also goes in mid position. As well and too usually go at the end of a clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "as well",
                        "too",
                        "also"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is not only rich she is famous ……………………………",
                    "description": "As well or too is possible here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "as well",
                        "too",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘She is pretty.’ ‘Her sister is …………………………’",
                    "description": "As well can be used in short answers. Also is not normally used in short answers.",
                    "answers": [
                        "also",
                        "as well"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It is a small house. …………………………, it needs a lot of repairs.",
                    "description": "Also can go at the beginning of a clause to refer to the whole clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Also",
                        "As well",
                        "Too"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is neither intelligent ........................................ smart.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "or",
                        "nor",
                        "either"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}